Ashwin Carvalho

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Software engineer with 1.5+ years of experience designing and building software applications using various programming languages, such as React, Ruby, and JavaScript. Experience with front-end and back-end development, including web frameworks like React, and database technologies like Postgres SQL. Proactive and collaborative team player, with excellent communication and problem-solving skills, and a commitment to continuous learning and self-improvement.

EXPERIENCE

BDO IN INDIA, Mumbai, India,

Technical Support Engineer, June 2023 - Present

- Handling fundamental technical problems in servers and portals.
- Maintaining the functionality of computer hardware and peripherals, and troubleshooting and debugging bugs in computer systems.
- Using remote desktop controller tools such as Manage Engine and Tight VNC, to provide rapid assistance.

MICROVERSE, Remote

Mentor (Volunteer), July 2022 - June 2023

- Mentor more than 5 junior web developers per week, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed innovative improvements to code organization resulting in a 20% improvement in code quality and a 15% improvement in overall performance.
- Provide 7 students with advice and tips for motivating them to maintain their longevity in the program.

SKYFOCUS TECHNOLOGY, Mumbai, India,

Software Developer, March 2021 - July 2022

- Developed a comprehensive Hospital Management Software and Online Application which supports over 5,000 users daily, streamlining appointment bookings and increasing online bookings by 35%.
- Engineered a School Management Software and Online Application that facilitated online admissions, increasing application submissions by 50% and supporting a school community of over 1,000 students and staff.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE, July 2022 - April 2023

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

SONOPANT DANDEKAR SHIKSHAN MANDAL, June 2018 – August 2021 B.Sc Computer Science

■ Completed a bachelor's Degree in Computer Science.

ALMABETTER, June 2021 - September 2021

Data Science

- This program took me on a journey of how Data Science helps identify insights from data/trends and understand usage patterns in large datasets.
- Learned data visualization to turn tabular data into a graphical form and how SQL is used to manage large datasets.

Degree & Certifications

■ Can be viewed online <u>here</u> and emailed on request.

ashwincarvalho27@gmail.com +917378931254 | Portfolio | LinkedIn | AngelList | GitHub | Twitter | Medium

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3.

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, Postgres SQL.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Render, Netlify, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools, Mobile / Responsive Development.

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Communication.

PROJECTS

Air Sports Club

- A website built for Air Sports Club to show detailed information about all air activities and their recent events.
- Built with: Html, CSS & JavaScript.
- Github Repo:- <u>Live-Link</u>

Metrics Webapp

- A web application to check a list of metrics (numeric values) that will create making use of React and Redux. Also using an API that provides numeric data about all Country Stats.
- Built with: Html, CSS, JavaScript & React-Redux.
- Github Repo:- <u>Live-Link</u>

Budget App

- A website to keep track of the budget. It shows the total amount that is spent on buying things and it also helps with budget management.
- Built with: Html, CSS, React & JavaScript.
- Github Repo:- Live-Link

Todo List App

- A todo list will help you to increase your productivity by prioritize the tasks that are more important and helps you to stay focused on the tasks that are the most important...
- Built with: Html, CSS & JavaScript.
- Github Repo:- Live-Link